<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>FreeBSD GNOME Project News</title>
    <link>http://www.FreeBSD.org/gnome/</link>
    <description>FreeBSD GNOME News System</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <webMaster>freebsd-gnome@FreeBSD.org (FreeBSD GNOME Team)</webMaster>
    <managingEditor>freebsd-gnome@FreeBSD.org (FreeBSD GNOME Team)</managingEditor>
    <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
    <ttl>120</ttl>
    <image>
      <url>http://www.FreeBSD.org/logo/logo-full.png</url>
      <title>FreeBSD GNOME Project News</title>
      <link>http://www.FreeBSD.org/gnome/</link>
    </image>
    <atom:link rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://www.FreeBSD.org/gnome/rss.xml"/>
    <item>
      <title>Announcing GNOME 2.32.1 for FreeBSD!</title>
      <description>Presenting GNOME 2.32.1 for FreeBSD. The official release
          notes for this release can be found at
          http://library.gnome.org/misc/release-notes/2.32/This will be the last release of the GNOME 2.x series, mainly a bugfix
          and bridge release to the first release of the GNOME 3.x series.This release features commits by avl, marcus, mezz and myself.The FreeBSD GNOME Team would like to thank the following contributors
          and testers for there help with this release:
        Zane C.B.
        
        romain@
        
        Olaf Seibert
        
        DomiX
        
        Bapt
        
        jsa@
        
        miwi@
        
        Sergio de Almeida Lenzi
        
        Maxim Samsonov
        
        Kris Moore
        
        </description>
      <link>http://www.FreeBSD.org/gnome/newsflash.html#event2010November19:0</link>
      <guid>http://www.FreeBSD.org/gnome/newsflash.html#event2010November19:0</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2010 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Announcing GNOME 2.30.1. for FreeBSD!</title>
      <description>Presenting GNOME 2.30.1 for FreeBSD. The official release
        notes for this release can be found at
        http://library.gnome.org/misc/release-notes/2.30/This release brings initial PackageKit support, Upower (replaces
        power management part of hal), cuse4bsd integration with HAL and cheese,
        and a faster Evolution.Sadly GNOME 2.30.x will be the last release with FreeBSD 6.X support.
        This will also be the last of the 2.x releases. The next release will
        be the highly-anticipated GNOME 3.0 which will bring with it a new UI
        experience.Currently, there are a few bugs with GNOME 2.30 that may be of note
        for our users. Be sure to consult the 2.30 upgrade FAQ at
        http://www.freebsd.org/gnome/docs/faq230.html
        for specific upgrading instructions, and the up-to-date list of known
        issues.This release features commits by: avl, ahze, bland, marcus, mezz
        and myself.The FreeBSD GNOME Team would like to thank Anders F Bjorklund for
        doing the initial packagekit porting.And the following contributors and testers for there help with this
        release:
        Eric L. Chen
        

        Vladimir Grebenschikov
        

        Sergio de Almeida Lenzi
        

        DomiX
        

        walder
        

        crsd
        

        Kevin Oberman
        

        Michal Varga
        

        Pavel Plesov
        

        Bapt
        

        kevin
        

        and Ion-Mihai Tetcu for running two exp-runs for us.
        
        </description>
      <link>http://www.FreeBSD.org/gnome/newsflash.html#event2010May10:0</link>
      <guid>http://www.FreeBSD.org/gnome/newsflash.html#event2010May10:0</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2010 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Announcing GNOME 2.28.1. for FreeBSD!</title>
      <description>Presenting GNOME 2.28.1 for FreeBSD. The official release
        notes for this release can be found at
        http://library.gnome.org/misc/release-notes/2.28/

        . Officially, this is mostly a polishing release in preparation
        for GNOME 3.0 due in about a year.On the FreeBSD front, though, a lot went into this release.
        Major thanks goes to kwm and avl who did a lot of the porting
        work for this release. In particular, kwm brought in Evolution
        MAPI support for better Microsoft Exchange integration. Avl
        made sure that the new gobject introspection repository ports
        were nicely compartmentalized so that large dependencies aren't
        brought in wholesale.But, every GNOME team member (ahze, avl, bland, kwm, mezz,
        and myself) contributed to this release.Other major improvements include an updated HAL with better
        volume probing code, ufsid integration, and support for volume
        names containing spaces (big thanks to J.R. Oldroyd); a new
        WebKit; updated AbiWord; an updated Gimp; and a preview of the
        new GNOME Shell project (thanks to Pawel Worach).The FreeBSD GNOME Team would like to that the following
        additional contributors to this release whose patches and
        testing really helped make it a success:
        Andrius Morkunas
        

        Dominique Goncalves
        

        Eric L. Chen
        

        J.R. Oldroyd
        

        Joseph S. Atkinson
        

        Li
        

        Pawel Worach
        

        Romain Tarti?re
        

        Thomas Vogt
        

        Yasuda Keisuke
        

        Rui Paulo
        

        Martin Wilke
        

        (and an extra shout out to miwi and pav for the pointyhat runs)
        
    	We would like to send this release out to Alexander Loginov
        (avl) in hopes that he feels better soon.</description>
      <link>http://www.FreeBSD.org/gnome/newsflash.html#event2009November28:0</link>
      <guid>http://www.FreeBSD.org/gnome/newsflash.html#event2009November28:0</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2009 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Announcing GNOME 2.26.0 for FreeBSD!</title>
      <description>The FreeBSD GNOME team is proud to announce the release of
          GNOME 2.26.0 for FreeBSD. The official release notes can be
          found at
          http://library.gnome.org/misc/release-notes/2.26/

          . On the FreeBSD front, we introduced a port of libxul 1.9 as
          an alternative for Firefox 2.0 as a Gecko provider. Almost
          all of the Gecko consumers can make use of this provider by
          setting:
          

          WITH_GECKO=libxul
          

          The GNOME 2.26 port was done by ahze, kwm, marcus, and mezz
          with contributions by Joseph S. Atkinson, Peter Wemm, Eric L.
          Chen, Martin Matuska, Craig Butler, and Pawel Worach.</description>
      <link>http://www.FreeBSD.org/gnome/newsflash.html#event2009April10:0</link>
      <guid>http://www.FreeBSD.org/gnome/newsflash.html#event2009April10:0</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2009 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Announcing GNOME 2.24.2 for FreeBSD!</title>
      <description>The FreeBSD GNOME team is proud to announce the release of
          GNOME 2.24.2 for FreeBSD. The official release notes can be
          found at
          http://library.gnome.org/misc/release-notes/2.24/

          . On the FreeBSD front, this release introduces Fuse support
          in HAL, adds multi-CPU support to libgtop, WebKit updates,
          and fixes some long-standing seahorse and gnome-keyring
          bugs.This release features commits by adamw, ahze, kwm, mezz,
          and myself. It would not have been possible without are
          contributors and testers: Alexander Loginov, Craig Butler,
          Dmitry Marakasov, Eric L. Chen, Joseph S. Atkinson, Kris
          Moore, Lapo Luchini, Nikos Ntarmos, Pawel Worach, Romain
          Tartiere, TAOKA Fumiyoshi, Romain Tartiere, Yasuda Keisuke,
          Zyl aZ, bf, Florent Thoumie, Peter Wemm, and pluknet.</description>
      <link>http://www.FreeBSD.org/gnome/newsflash.html#event2009January9:0</link>
      <guid>http://www.FreeBSD.org/gnome/newsflash.html#event2009January9:0</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 9 Jan 2009 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Announcing GNOME 2.22.0 for FreeBSD!</title>
      <description>The FreeBSD GNOME team is proud to announce the release of
          GNOME 2.22.0 for FreeBSD. The official GNOME 2.22 release
          notes can be found at
          http://library.gnome.org/misc/release-notes/2.22/

          . On the FreeBSD front, this release features an updated hal
          port with support for video4linux devices, DRM (Direct
          Rendering), and better support of removable media. Work is
          also underway to tie webkit more closely into GNOME. As part
          of the GNOME 2.22 upgrade, GStreamer received a rather large
          upgrade as well. Be sure to consult UPDATING on the proper
          steps to upgrade all of your GNOME ports.This release would not have been possible without the
          contributions and testing efforts of the following people:
          Pawel Worach, kan, edwin, Peter Ulrich Kruppa, J. W.
          Ballantine, Yasuda Keisuke, and Andriy Gapon.</description>
      <link>http://www.FreeBSD.org/gnome/newsflash.html#event2008March24:0</link>
      <guid>http://www.FreeBSD.org/gnome/newsflash.html#event2008March24:0</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2008 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Announcing GNOME 2.20.1 for FreeBSD!</title>
      <description>Presenting GNOME 2.20.1 and all related works for FreeBSD.
          The official GNOME 2.20 release notes can be found at
          http://www.gnome.org/start/2.20/notes/en/

          . Beyond that, this update includes the new GIMP 2.4
          (courtesy of ahze).The GNOME 2.20 update also includes a huge change in the
          FreeBSD GNOME hierarchy. We are now using the more standard
          DATADIR of ${PREFIX}/share rather than ${PREFIX}/share/gnome.
          The result is that fewer patches and hacks are needed to port
          GNOME components to FreeBSD. This will mean some user changes
          may be required, so be sure to read /usr/ports/UPDATING for
          more details.This release and the things we accomplished in it would
          not have been possible without mezz's crazy idea to collapse
          DATADIR, and his persistence to make it happen successfully.
          Ahze and pav also deserve thanks for their work on porting
          modules and testing the whole ball of wax on pointyhat
          (respectively).The FreeBSD GNOME team would also like to thank our
          various testers and contributors:Yasuda Keisuke
          

          Frank Jahnke
          

          Pawel Worach
          

          Brian Gruber
          

          Franz Klammer
          

          Yuri Pankov
          

          Nick Barkas
          

          Cristian KLEIN
          

          Tony Maher
          

          Scot Hetzel
          

          Martin Matuska (mm)
          

          Benoit Dejean
          

          Martin Wilke (miwi)
          

          (And anyone else I may have missed)</description>
      <link>http://www.FreeBSD.org/gnome/newsflash.html#event2007October24:0</link>
      <guid>http://www.FreeBSD.org/gnome/newsflash.html#event2007October24:0</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2007 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GNOME 2.19.6 available for FreeBSD</title>
      <description>Okay, okay, I have missed a few updates. But the FreeBSD
          GNOME team has not been slacking. We've been keeping up with
          the latest GNOME development releases including this
          http://mail.gnome.org/archives/devel-announce-list/2007-August/msg00000.html

          . Checkout the ports and
          ../gnome/docs/faq2.html#q21

          to see where GNOME 2.20 currently stands. Since 2.10 Beta 1
          is right around the corner, now is also the time to start
          putting together some killer FreeBSD GNOME screenshots. Send
          all submissions to
          mailto:freebsd-gnome@FreeBSD.org

          .</description>
      <link>http://www.FreeBSD.org/gnome/newsflash.html#event2007August4:0</link>
      <guid>http://www.FreeBSD.org/gnome/newsflash.html#event2007August4:0</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 4 Aug 2007 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GNOME 2.19.3 available for FreeBSD</title>
      <description>The third release on the path to GNOME 2.20 is now
          available in both port and
          ../gnome/docs/faq2.html#q21

          forms. There is one known build issue with
          gnome-system-monitor and FreeBSD &lt; 7-CURRENT that we hope
          to have worked out soon. Along with this release comes the
          GNOME 2.20 (and beyond!)
          http://live.gnome.org/RoadMap

          . This will prepare you for the exciting new features in
          store for our favorite Desktop Environment.</description>
      <link>http://www.FreeBSD.org/gnome/newsflash.html#event2007June9:0</link>
      <guid>http://www.FreeBSD.org/gnome/newsflash.html#event2007June9:0</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 9 Jun 2007 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GNOME 2.18.2 available for FreeBSD</title>
      <description>The next bug fix release for GNOME 2.18 has been
          http://mail.gnome.org/archives/devel-announce-list/2007-May/msg00004.html

          and ports and
          ../gnome/docs/faq2.html#q21

          are available for FreeBSD. So the only question is, why
          haven't you upgraded yet?</description>
      <link>http://www.FreeBSD.org/gnome/newsflash.html#event2007May31:0</link>
      <guid>http://www.FreeBSD.org/gnome/newsflash.html#event2007May31:0</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2007 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
