<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<article xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:lang="en">
  <info><title xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">Filtering Bridges</title>
    

    <authorgroup xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
      <author xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><personname xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><firstname xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">Alex</firstname><surname xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">Dupre</surname></personname><affiliation xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
          <address xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><email xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">ale@FreeBSD.org</email></address>
        </affiliation></author>
    </authorgroup>

    <legalnotice xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xml:id="trademarks" role="trademarks">
      <para xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">FreeBSD is a registered trademark of
  the FreeBSD Foundation.</para>
      <para xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">3Com and HomeConnect are registered
  trademarks of 3Com Corporation.</para>
      <para xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">Intel, Celeron, Centrino, Core, EtherExpress, i386,
  i486, Itanium, Pentium, and Xeon are trademarks or registered
  trademarks of Intel Corporation or its subsidiaries in the United
  States and other countries.</para>
      <para xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">Many of the designations used by
  manufacturers and sellers to distinguish their products are claimed
  as trademarks.  Where those designations appear in this document,
  and the FreeBSD Project was aware of the trademark claim, the
  designations have been followed by the <quote xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">&#8482;</quote> or the
  <quote xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">®</quote> symbol.</para>
    </legalnotice>

    <pubdate xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">$FreeBSD$</pubdate>

    <releaseinfo xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">$FreeBSD$</releaseinfo>

    <abstract xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
      <para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">Often it is useful to divide one physical network (like an
	Ethernet) into two separate segments without having to create subnets,
	and use a router to link them together. The device that connects the
	two networks in this way is called a bridge.  A FreeBSD system with
	two network interfaces is enough in order to act as a bridge.</para>

      <para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">A bridge works by scanning the addresses of <acronym xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">MAC</acronym>
	level (Ethernet addresses) of the devices connected to each of its
	network interfaces and then forwarding the traffic between the two
	networks only if the source and the destination are on different
	segments. Under many points of view a bridge is similar to an Ethernet
	switch with only two ports.</para>
    </abstract>
  </info>

  <sect1 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xml:id="filtering-bridges-why">
    <title xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">Why use a filtering bridge?</title>

    <para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">More and more frequently, thanks to the lowering costs of broad band
      Internet connections (xDSL) and also because of the reduction of
      available IPv4 addresses, many companies are connected to the Internet
      24 hours on 24 and with few (sometimes not even a power of 2) IP
      addresses. In these situations it is often desirable to have a firewall
      that filters incoming and outgoing traffic from and towards Internet,
      but a packet filtering solution based on router may not be applicable,
      either due to subnetting issues, the router is owned by the connectivity
      supplier (<acronym xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">ISP</acronym>), or because it does not support such
      functionalities. In these scenarios the use of a filtering bridge is
      highly advised.</para>

    <para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">A bridge-based firewall can be configured and inserted between the
      xDSL router and your Ethernet hub/switch without any IP numbering
      issues.</para>
  </sect1>

  <sect1 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xml:id="filtering-bridges-how">
    <title xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">How to Install</title>

    <para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">Adding bridge functionalities to a FreeBSD system is not difficult.
      Since 4.5 release it is possible to load such functionalities as modules
      instead of having to rebuild the kernel, simplifying the procedure a
      great deal. In the following subsections I will explain both
      installation ways.</para>

    <important xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
      <para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><emphasis xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">Do not</emphasis> follow both instructions: a procedure
	<emphasis xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">excludes</emphasis> the other one.  Select the best choice
	according to your needs and abilities.</para>
    </important>

    <para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">Before going on, be sure to have at least two Ethernet cards that
      support the promiscuous mode for both reception and transmission, since
      they must be able to send Ethernet packets with any address, not just
      their own. Moreover, to have a good throughput, the cards should be PCI
      bus mastering cards. The best choices are still the Intel <trademark xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">EtherExpress</trademark>
      Pro, followed by the <trademark xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" class="registered">3Com</trademark> 3c9xx series. To simplify the firewall
      configuration it may be useful to have two cards of different
      manufacturers (using different drivers) in order to distinguish clearly
      which interface is connected to the router and which to the inner
      network.</para>

    <sect2 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xml:id="filtering-bridges-kernel">
      <title xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">Kernel Configuration</title>

      <para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">So you have decided to use the older but well tested installation
	method. To begin, you have to add the following rows to your kernel
	configuration file:</para>

      <programlisting xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">options BRIDGE
options IPFIREWALL
options IPFIREWALL_VERBOSE</programlisting>

      <para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">The first line is to compile the bridge support, the second one is
	the firewall and the third one is the logging functions of the
	firewall.</para>

      <para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">Now it is necessary to build and install the new kernel.  You may
	find detailed instructions in the <link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="../../../../doc/en_US.ISO8859-1/books/handbook/kernelconfig-building.html">Building
	and Installing a Custom Kernel</link> section of the FreeBSD
	Handbook.</para>
    </sect2>

    <sect2 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xml:id="filtering-bridges-modules">
      <title xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">Modules Loading</title>

      <para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">If you have chosen to use the new and simpler installation
	method, the only thing to do now is add the following row to
        <filename xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">/boot/loader.conf</filename>:</para>

      <programlisting xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">bridge_load="YES"</programlisting>

      <para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">In this way, during the system startup, the
	<filename xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">bridge.ko</filename> module will be loaded together with the
	kernel. It is not required to add a similar row for the
	<filename xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">ipfw.ko</filename> module, since it will be loaded
	automatically after the execution of the steps in the following
	section.</para>
    </sect2>
  </sect1>

  <sect1 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xml:id="filtering-bridges-finalprep">
    <title xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">Final Preparation</title>

    <para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">Before rebooting in order to load the new kernel or the required
      modules (according to the previously chosen installation method), you
      have to make some changes to the <filename xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">/etc/rc.conf</filename>
      configuration file. The default rule of the firewall is to reject all IP
      packets.  Initially we will set up an <option xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">open</option> firewall, in order to verify
      its operation without any issue related to packet filtering (in case you
      are going to execute this procedure remotely, such configuration will
      avoid you to remain isolated from the network). Put these lines in
      <filename xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">/etc/rc.conf</filename>:</para>

    <programlisting xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">firewall_enable="YES"
firewall_type="open"
firewall_quiet="YES"
firewall_logging="YES"</programlisting>

    <para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">The first row will enable the firewall (and will load the module
      <filename xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">ipfw.ko</filename> if it is not compiled in the kernel), the
      second one to set up it in <option xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">open</option> mode (as explained in
      <filename xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">/etc/rc.firewall</filename>), the third one to not show rules
      loading and the fourth one to enable logging support.</para>

    <para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">About the configuration of the network interfaces, the most used way
      is to assign an IP to only one of the network cards, but the bridge will
      work equally even if both interfaces or none has a configured IP. In the
      last case (IP-less) the bridge machine will be still more hidden, as
      inaccessible from the network: to configure it, you have to login from
      console or through a third network interface separated from the bridge.
      Sometimes, during the system startup, some programs require network
      access, say for domain resolution: in this case it is necessary to
      assign an IP to the external interface (the one connected to Internet,
      where <acronym xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">DNS</acronym> server resides), since the bridge will be
      activated at the end of the startup procedure. It means that the
      <filename xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">fxp0</filename> interface (in our case) must be mentioned
      in the ifconfig section of the <filename xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">/etc/rc.conf</filename> file,
      while the <filename xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">xl0</filename> is not. Assigning an IP to both
      the network cards does not make much sense, unless, during the start
      procedure, applications should access to services on both Ethernet
      segments.</para>

    <para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">There is another important thing to know. When running IP over
      Ethernet, there are actually two Ethernet protocols in use: one is IP,
      the other is <acronym xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">ARP</acronym>.  <acronym xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">ARP</acronym> does the
      conversion of the IP address of a host into its Ethernet address
      (<acronym xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">MAC</acronym> layer).  In order to allow the communication
      between two hosts separated by the bridge, it is necessary that the
      bridge will forward <acronym xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">ARP</acronym> packets. Such protocol is not
      included in the IP layer, since it exists only with IP over Ethernet.
      The FreeBSD firewall filters exclusively on the IP layer and therefore
      all non-IP packets (<acronym xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">ARP</acronym> included) will be forwarded
      without being filtered, even if the firewall is configured to not permit
      anything.</para>

    <para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">Now it is time to reboot the system and use it as before: there will
      be some new messages about the bridge and the firewall, but the bridge
      will not be activated and the firewall, being in <option xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">open</option> mode, will not
      avoid any operations.</para>

    <para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">If there are any problems, you should sort them out now
      before proceeding.</para>
  </sect1>

  <sect1 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xml:id="filtering-bridges-enabling">
    <title xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">Enabling the Bridge</title>

    <para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">At this point, to enable the bridge, you have to execute the
      following commands (having the shrewdness to replace the names of the
      two network interfaces <filename xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">fxp0</filename> and
      <filename xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">xl0</filename> with your own ones):</para>

    <screen xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><prompt xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">#</prompt> <userinput xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">sysctl net.link.ether.bridge.config=fxp0:0,xl0:0</userinput>
<prompt xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">#</prompt> <userinput xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">sysctl net.link.ether.bridge.ipfw=1</userinput>
<prompt xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">#</prompt> <userinput xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">sysctl net.link.ether.bridge.enable=1</userinput></screen>

    <para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">The first row specifies which interfaces should be activated by the
      bridge, the second one will enable the firewall on the bridge and
      finally the third one will enable the bridge.</para>

    <note xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
      <para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">If you have FreeBSD 5.1-RELEASE or previous the sysctl variables
	are spelled differently.  See <citerefentry xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><refentrytitle xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">bridge</refentrytitle><manvolnum xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">4</manvolnum></citerefentry> for details.</para>
    </note>

    <para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">At this point you should be able to insert the machine between two
      sets of hosts without compromising any communication abilities between
      them. If so, the next step is to add the
      <literal xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">net.link.ether.bridge.<replaceable xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">[blah]</replaceable>=<replaceable xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">[blah]</replaceable></literal>
      portions of these rows to the <filename xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">/etc/sysctl.conf</filename>
      file, in order to have them execute at startup.</para>
  </sect1>

  <sect1 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xml:id="filtering-bridges-ipfirewall">
    <title xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">Configuring The Firewall</title>

    <para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">Now it is time to create your own file with custom firewall rules,
      in order to secure the inside network. There will be some complication
      in doing this because not all of the firewall functionalities are
      available on bridged packets. Furthermore, there is a difference between
      the packets that are in the process of being forwarded and packets that
      are being received by the local machine. In general, incoming packets
      are run through the firewall only once, not twice as is normally the
      case; in fact they are filtered only upon receipt, so rules that use
      <option xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">out</option> or <option xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">xmit</option> will never match. Personally, I use <option xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">in via</option> which is an
      older syntax, but one that has a sense when you read it. Another
      limitation is that you are restricted to use only <option xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">pass</option> or <option xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">drop</option>
      commands for packets filtered by a bridge.  Sophisticated things like
      <option xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">divert</option>, <option xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">forward</option> or <option xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">reject</option> are not available. Such options can
      still be used, but only on traffic to or from the bridge machine itself
      (if it has an IP address).</para>

    <para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">New in FreeBSD 4.0, is the concept of stateful filtering.  This is a
      big improvement for <acronym xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">UDP</acronym> traffic, which typically is a
      request going out, followed shortly thereafter by a response with the
      exact same set of IP addresses and port numbers (but with source and
      destination reversed, of course). For firewalls that have no
      statekeeping, there is almost no way to deal with this sort of traffic
      as a single session. But with a firewall that can <quote xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">remember</quote> an outgoing
      <acronym xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">UDP</acronym> packet and, for the next few minutes, allow a
      response, handling <acronym xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">UDP</acronym> services is trivial. The
      following example shows how to do it. It is possible to do the same thing
      with <acronym xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">TCP</acronym> packets. This allows you to avoid some
      denial of service attacks and other nasty tricks, but it also typically
      makes your state table grow quickly in size.</para>

    <para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">Let's look at an example setup. Note first that at the top of
      <filename xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">/etc/rc.firewall</filename> there are already standard rules
      for the loopback interface <filename xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">lo0</filename>, so we should not
      have to care for them anymore. Custom rules should be put in a separate
      file (say <filename xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">/etc/rc.firewall.local</filename>) and loaded at
      system startup, by modifying the row of
      <filename xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">/etc/rc.conf</filename> where we defined the <option xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">open</option>
      firewall:</para>

    <programlisting xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">firewall_type="/etc/rc.firewall.local"</programlisting>

    <important xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
      <para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">You have to specify the <emphasis xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">full</emphasis> path, otherwise
	it will not be loaded with the risk to remain isolated from the
	network.</para>
    </important>

    <para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">For our example imagine to have the <filename xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">fxp0</filename>
      interface connected towards the outside (Internet) and the
      <filename xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">xl0</filename> towards the inside
      (<acronym xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">LAN</acronym>).  The bridge machine has the IP <systemitem xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" class="ipaddress">1.2.3.4</systemitem> (it is not possible that your
      <acronym xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">ISP</acronym> can give you an address quite like this, but for
      our example it is good).</para>

    <programlisting xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"># Things that we have kept state on before get to go through in a hurry
add check-state

# Throw away RFC 1918 networks
add drop all from 10.0.0.0/8 to any in via fxp0
add drop all from 172.16.0.0/12 to any in via fxp0
add drop all from 192.168.0.0/16 to any in via fxp0

# Allow the bridge machine to say anything it wants
# (if the machine is IP-less do not include these rows)
add pass tcp from 1.2.3.4 to any setup keep-state
add pass udp from 1.2.3.4 to any keep-state
add pass ip from 1.2.3.4 to any

# Allow the inside hosts to say anything they want
add pass tcp from any to any in via xl0 setup keep-state
add pass udp from any to any in via xl0 keep-state
add pass ip from any to any in via xl0

# TCP section
# Allow SSH
add pass tcp from any to any 22 in via fxp0 setup keep-state
# Allow SMTP only towards the mail server
add pass tcp from any to relay 25 in via fxp0 setup keep-state
# Allow zone transfers only by the slave name server [dns2.nic.it]
add pass tcp from 193.205.245.8 to ns 53 in via fxp0 setup keep-state
# Pass ident probes.  It is better than waiting for them to timeout
add pass tcp from any to any 113 in via fxp0 setup keep-state
# Pass the "quarantine" range
add pass tcp from any to any 49152-65535 in via fxp0 setup keep-state

# UDP section
# Allow DNS only towards the name server
add pass udp from any to ns 53 in via fxp0 keep-state
# Pass the "quarantine" range
add pass udp from any to any 49152-65535 in via fxp0 keep-state

# ICMP section
# Pass 'ping'
add pass icmp from any to any icmptypes 8 keep-state
# Pass error messages generated by 'traceroute'
add pass icmp from any to any icmptypes 3
add pass icmp from any to any icmptypes 11

# Everything else is suspect
add drop log all from any to any</programlisting>

    <para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">Those of you who have set up firewalls before may notice some things
      missing. In particular, there are no anti-spoofing rules, in fact we did
      <emphasis xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">not</emphasis> add:</para>

    <programlisting xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">add deny all from 1.2.3.4/8 to any in via fxp0</programlisting>

    <para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">That is, drop packets that are coming in from the outside claiming
      to be from our network. This is something that you would commonly do to
      be sure that someone does not try to evade the packet filter, by
      generating nefarious packets that look like they are from the inside.
      The problem with that is that there is <emphasis xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">at least</emphasis> one
      host on the outside interface that you do not want to ignore: the
      router. But usually, the <acronym xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">ISP</acronym> anti-spoofs at their
      router, so we do not need to bother that much.</para>

    <para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">The last rule seems to be an exact duplicate of the default rule,
      that is, do not let anything pass that is not specifically allowed. But
      there is a difference: all suspected traffic will be logged.</para>

    <para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">There are two rules for passing <acronym xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">SMTP</acronym> and
      <acronym xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">DNS</acronym> traffic towards the mail server and the name
      server, if you have them. Obviously the whole rule set should be
      flavored to personal taste, this is only a specific example (rule format
      is described accurately in the <citerefentry xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><refentrytitle xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">ipfw</refentrytitle><manvolnum xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">8</manvolnum></citerefentry> man page). Note that in
      order for <quote xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">relay</quote> and <quote xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">ns</quote> to work, name service lookups must work
      <emphasis xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">before</emphasis> the bridge is enabled. This is an example of
      making sure that you set the IP on the correct network card.
      Alternatively it is possible to specify the IP address instead of the
      host name (required if the machine is IP-less).</para>

    <para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">People that are used to setting up firewalls are probably also used
      to either having a <option xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">reset</option> or a <option xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">forward</option> rule for ident packets
      (<acronym xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">TCP</acronym> port 113). Unfortunately, this is not an
      applicable option with the bridge, so the best thing is to simply pass
      them to their destination. As long as that destination machine is not
      running an ident daemon, this is relatively harmless. The alternative is
      dropping connections on port 113, which creates some problems with
      services like <acronym xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">IRC</acronym> (the ident probe must
      timeout).</para>

    <para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">The only other thing that is a little weird that you may have
      noticed is that there is a rule to let the bridge machine speak, and
      another for internal hosts. Remember that this is because the two sets
      of traffic will take different paths through the kernel and into the
      packet filter. The inside net will go through the bridge, while the
      local machine will use the normal IP stack to speak. Thus the two rules
      to handle the different cases. The <literal xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">in via
      fxp0</literal> rules work for both paths. In general, if
      you use <option xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">in via</option> rules throughout the filter, you will need to make an
      exception for locally generated packets, because they did not come in
      via any of our interfaces.</para>
  </sect1>

  <sect1 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xml:id="filtering-bridges-contributors">
    <title xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">Contributors</title>

    <para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">Many parts of this article have been taken, updated and adapted from
      an old text about bridging, edited by Nick Sayer. A pair of inspirations
      are due to an introduction on bridging by Steve Peterson.</para>

    <para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">A big thanks to Luigi Rizzo for the implementation of the bridge
      code in FreeBSD and for the time he has dedicated to me answering all of
      my related questions.</para>

    <para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">A thanks goes out also to Tom Rhodes who looked over my job of
      translation from Italian (the original language of this article) into
      English.</para>
  </sect1>
</article>
